Finding aid for the Los Angeles Alliance for a New Economy records, 1987-2013 LSC.2252
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Campaign Files, 1990-circa 2003
  - Long Beach Coalition for Good Jobs and a Healthy Community
    - Los Angeles Living Wage
      - Letters to City Council, (1996) (Box 15)
        Appears to be related to United Electrical Radio and Machine Workers of America (UE).
      - Letters to City Council (8 files), (1996) (Box 16)
      - Leveraging Health Insurance through Living Wage Policy, (2000 Feb) (Box 18)
      - List of Companies to Leaflet, (undated) (Box 14)
      - Living Wage, (1997) (Box 15)
        Collective Bargaining Agreement By and Between AMPCO System Parking (Los Angeles International Airport) and California Teamsters Public, Professional and Medical Employees Union Local 911 Affiliated with International Brotherhood of Teamsters
      - Living Wage, (1997) (Box 15)
      - Living Wage, (1997) (Box 5)
      - Living Wage, (1996) (Box 5)
      - Living Wage (11 files), (1998-2003) (Box 10)
      - Living Wage Academics, (1996) (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Living Wage Action press packet (2 files), (1998) (Box 13)
      - Living Wage Amendment Delegation, (1998 Sep 25) (Box 6)
      - Living Wage Amendment Vote, (1998 Nov 10) (Box 9)
      - Living Wage articles, (1999) (Box 5)
      - Living Wage Articles (3 files), (1996-1997) (Box 15)
      - Living Wage Articles and Research, (1996) (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Living Wage BCA Situation, (1998) (Box 9)
      - Living Wage Binder, (1998) (Box 6)
      - Living wage business correspondence, (circa 1997) (Box 14)
      - Living Wage business materials, information, etc., (1996-1997) (Box 14)
      - Living Wage business task force; notes, lists, (circa 1997) (Box 14)
      - Living Wage Coalition, (1997) (Box 15)
      - Living Wage Coalition, (2000) (Box 13)
      - Living Wage Coalition (AFL- CIO/ACORN) information, (1996) (Box 13)
      - Living Wage Coalition First Year Report about Living Wage Ordinance, (1998) (Box 6)
      - Living Wage Coalition Garment Industry research, (1996 Dec) (Box 14)
      - Living Wage Coalition Graphics, (1996) (Box 16)
        Letter from Baltimore CARE (Commission on Aging and Retirement Education).
      - Living Wage Coalition letters to funders, (circa 1996) (Box 14)
      - Living Wage Coalition Meetings/Correspondence, (1997) (Box 6)
      - Living Wage Coalition- request for Public records memos and correspondence, (1996) (Box 13)
      - Living Wage Coalition Steering Committee, (1998) (Box 5)
      - Living Wage Coalitions' complimentary letter regarding CAO, (1999) (Box 7)
      - Living Wage Coverage at Airport, (1997-1998) (Box 5)
      - Living Wage document, (circa 1996) (Box 14)
      - Living Wage Earned Income Flyers non-English, (undated) (Box 13)
        Contains translations in Amharic, Chinese, Hmong, Korean, Laotian, Tagalog, and Vietnamese.
      - Living Wage Economic Impact Survey, (1996) (Box 15)
      - Living Wage for Los Angeles Workshop (A), (1996) (Box 6)
      - Living Wage General, (1996) (Box 14)
      - Living Wage: In The Public Interest? Increasing the Quality of Life for Families and Communities in Los Angeles, California (The) by A Chicago Institute on Urban Poverty, (1996) (Box 15)
      - Living Wage Individual Membership, (1996) (Box 15)
      - Living Wage Letters, (1997) (Box 15)
      - Living Wage letters, (1997) (Box 13)
      - Living Wage Los Angeles (4 files), (1996-1997) (Box 15)
      - Living Wage Opponents, (1999) (Box 13)
      - Living Wage Ordinance, (circa 1996) (Box 15)
        Assortment of holographic notes, messages and lists.
      - Living Wage Ordinance, (1997-1998) (Box 13)
      - Living Wage Ordinance (2 files), (1999) (Box 9)
      - Living Wage Ordinance (4 files), (1999) (Box 13)
      - Living Wage Ordinance (photocopy of ordinance), (1999) (Box 14)
      - Living Wage Ordinance and Worker Retention Ordinance, (1998) (Box 18)
      - Living Wage Ordinance compilation of compliant investigation, (1999) (Box 5)
      - Living Wage Ordinance Content, (1997) (Box 16)
      - Living Wage Ordinance Council Advocacy, (1997) (Box 14)
      - Living Wage Ordinance Drafts, (1998) (Box 7)
      - Living Wage Ordinance Legal Memos, (1996) (Box 6)
      - Living Wage Ordinance Legal Memos, (2000) (Box 7)
      - Living Wage Ordinance Miscellaneous Documents, (1997) (Box 7)
      - Living Wage Ordinance Propriety Department Issue, (1997) (Box 16)
      - Living Wage Ordinance Regulations BCA (Bureau of Contract Administration), (1997) (Box 7)
      - Living Wage Ordinance supporters, (undated) (Box 15)
      - Living Wage poll, (1997 Jan) (Box 14)
      - Living Wage Projects (9 files), (1999) (Box 10)
      - Living Wage Regulation, (1999) (Box 5)
      - Living Wage Regulations, (2000) (Box 14)
      - Living Wage Sign-up Sheets, (1996 Dec 18) (Box 15)
      - Living Wage Strategy Committee (2 files), (1995) (Box 15)
      - Living Wage Studies, (undated) (Box 14)
      - Living Wage Study ($10 per hour proposal), (2000) (Box 18)
      - Living Wage Summary (LA Times poll), (1997 Mar) (Box 15)
      - Living Wage Surveys, (2002) (Box 25)
      - Living Wage Technical Assistance Meeting, (1995-1996) (Box 13)
      - Living Wage Theater Contacts, (undated) (Box 15)
      - Living Wage Workshop Sign-in, (1996 Feb 3) (Box 15)
      - Lobbying Ordinance (3 files), (1997) (Box 12)
      - Lockhead Martin Information Management Services, (1996) (Box 13)
      - Los Angeles Chamber of Commerce, (1996) (Box 13)
      - Los Angeles City Council Meeting ([3/4 inch U-matic] videotape recording), (1997 Mar 18) (Box 34)
      - Los Angeles County Living Wage Ordinance, (1999) (Box 13)
      - Los Angeles Living Wage, (1996 Dec 3) (Box 17, Folder 31)
      - Los Angeles Living Wage Coalition Meetings, (1998) (Box 6)
      - Los Angeles Living Wage Coalition press releases, (1998) (Box 5)
      - Los Angeles Living Wage Demonstration (LALW) A Christmas Carol at City Hall footage (VHS recording), (1996 Dec 18) (Box 35)
      - Los Angeles living wage organization individual memberships, (circa 1996) (Box 14)
      - Los Angeles Metropolitan Alliance Living Wage, (1999-2000) (Box 10)
      - Los Angeles Secession Information, (2002) (Box 6)
      - Low Wage Poverty Research, (1995) (Box 16)
      - Low Wage Worker Campaign, (2003) (Box 6)
      - Mayoral Race articles, (1997) (Box 5)
      - Mayors Business Advocacy, (1996) (Box 14)
      - Mayor's Office, (1996) (Box 14)
      - Minimum Labor Standard Chart, (circa 1995) (Box 17, Folder 34)
      - Motion, (1996 Jul 3) (Box 16)
      - National Lawyers Guild Living Wage, (1997) (Box 17, Folder 37)
      - National Living Wage Survey, (undated) (Box 15)
      - National Minimum Wage Meeting Notes, (1996) (Box 17, Folder 33)
      - New Haven Living Wage, (1997) (Box 9)
      - Nexis information literature, (1991) (Box 13)
      - NLG (National Lawyers Guild)Committee Economic Rights, (1997) (Box 16)
      - No More Candy Store: States and cities Making Job Subsidies Accountable by Greg Le Roy, (1994) (Box 15)
      - North Hollywood/Valley Jobs, (undated) (Box 7)
      - Old Compliance Information, (1997) (Box 7)
      - Olvera Street, (2000) (Box 18)
      - Ontario Airport (2 files), (1997) (Box 13)
      - Ontario Worker contacts, (1997) (Box 17, Folder 46)
      - Organizational Letters to City Council, (1996) (Box 13)
      - Organizational Letters to Council (2 files), (1997) (Box 13)
      - Other Cities, (1997) (Box 17, Folder 30)
      - Other Opponents, (1995) (Box 13)
      - Outreach Educational Materials (2 files), (1997) (Box 13)
      - Pacific Shores Union Card Check publicity, (undated) (Box 7)
      - Personnel Committee Hearing Materials, (1998 May 20) (Box 6)
      - Playa Vista Living Wage (3 files), (1999) (Box 10)
      - Police Academy (General Services), (1998) (Box 18)
      - Ports O'Call Court Case, (1997) (Box 18)
      - Press Packet Ingredient Pieces (clippings), (1996) (Box 5)
      - Prevailing Wage Information, (1994-1995) (Box 17, Folder 41)
      - PRIMA Contracting Reform, (2000) (Box 7)
      - Pro Labor and Anti, State of Labor Movement articles, (1996-1997) (Box 5)
      - Producers' Support Letter, (1996 Dec 16) (Box 15)
      - Profitability Study, (1996) (Box 15)
      - Proposed Areas of Research, (1995) (Box 13)
      - Public Relations Strategy Committee Sub-Committee Materials and Press, (1993-1996) (Box 14)
      - Rec & Park Workers, (2000-2001) (Box 13)
      - Regulations for Living Wage Ordinance and SCWRO (Service Contractor Worker Retention Ordinance) [draft?], (1999) (Box 7)
      - Reinforcement, (1998) (Box 6)
      - Religious Groups and Living Wage, (1997-1999) (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - Research, (1996-1998) (Box 5)
      - Rick Sanders Report, (1998 Aug 20) (Box 6)
      - Sample Phonebook Delegation Instructions, (1995-1997) (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Sander's Living Wage Evaluation, (1999) (Box 6)
      - Sander's Report, (1998 May 20) (Box 7)
      - Sears Site, (2001) (Box 8)
      - Senator Tom Hayden, (1997) (Box 12)
      - Signed business support letters, (circa 1997-1999) (Box 14)
      - Small business (Anti-affirmative Action Sentiment Takes Toll article), (1996 Apr) (Box 14)
      - Southeast Los Angeles: Community Plan Revision Program area plan, (1998 Mar) (Box 6)
      - Stephanie Luce, (1998) (Box 12)
      - Strategic Planning, (1999) (Box 7)
      - Subsidy Accountability Project, (1998) (Box 8)
      - Subsidy Contract Abuse Survey, (undated) (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Subsidy Promotional item, (1997 Feb 28) (Box 16)
      - Summary of Compromises to Original Living Wage Ordinance, (1997 Mar) (Box 15)
      - Svorinich Motion, (circa 1996) (Box 14)
      - Svorinich Motion, (1997 Mar) (Box 14)
      - Sweeney Address Press Packet, (1997 Feb 14) (Box 5)
      - Target Research, (1996) (Box 16)
      - Terminal petitions (6 files), (1997) (Box 13)
      - Tom Hayden Propaganda, (undated) (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Unsent Worker letters, (undated) (Box 17, Folder 44)
      - USC (3 files), (1999) (Box 11)
      - Valley Industry and Commerce Association information packet, (1996) (Box 14)
      - Walter Prince, (1996) (Box 13)
      - Welfare Reform, (1997) (Box 17, Folder 13)
        Information package on "Forging an Interfaith Response to the Welfare Crisis in Los Angeles County."
      - Where Los Angeles Magazine, (1994 Feb) (Box 9)
      - Which Way, L.A.? (audio cassette recording), (2002 Mar 14) (Box 35)
      - Worker letters to City Council, (1999) (Box 13)
      - Worker Profile, (1996) (Box 17, Folder 43)
      - Worker Profiles, (circa 1996) (Box 17, Folder 45)
      - Worker Retention- Charts/Letters, (1996-1997) (Box 7)
      - Worker Retention Ordinance (4 files), (1999) (Box 9)
      - Worker Retention Reports, (1996) (Box 13)
      - Worker's Retention/ Living Wage Ordinances, (circa 1996) (Box 14)
      - WRO (Worker Retention Ordinance), (1999) (Box 5)
  - Respect at LAX
    - Airline Arguments, (1998) (Box 18)
    - Airport Layoffs, (2002) (Box 5)
    - Airport Living Wage, (1997) (Box 18)
    - Airport McDonalds Living Wage (11 files), (2002) (Box 8)
    - Airport Retail Concession Structures, (2001) (Box 5)
    - Airport Workers Living Wage Complaints (8 files), (1998-2002) (Box 18)
    - Airports Responsible Contractor, (2001-2003) (Box 5)
    - BOAC appointments, (2001) (Box 5)
    - Duty Free Concession at LAX, (1998-1999) (Box 18)
    - Earned Income Credit Outreach Campaign publicity packet, (2001) (Box 13)
    - General Concession Food/Retail Correspondence, (2001-2002) (Box 5)
    - Globe Aviation Service revised vacation and sick policy (LAX and ONT), (2001) (Box 14)
    - Globe Aviation Services Ontario and LAX Policy Vacation, (2000) (Box 14)
    - Huntleigh Complaint Letter to City of Los Angeles Office, (2001) (Box 13)
    - LAWA (Los Angeles World Airports) Responsible Contract, (2004) (Box 5)
    - LAX Economic Assessment Task Force, (2001) (Box 6)
    - LAX Taskforce/ LA Taskforce, (2002) (Box 5)
    - Living Wage Task Force Current, (2000-2002) (Box 6)
    - Los Angeles Newspaper Articles- Workers, (2002) (Box 5)
    - McDonald's NLRB (National Labor Relations Board) Charge, (2002) (Box 8)
    - McDonalds-related (2 files), (2002) (Box 10)
    - National Airport Help, (2003) (Box 6)
    - New Question and Answer Ordinances (2 files), (2001) (Box 14)
    - Ontario Airport Concession Expirations, (2004) (Box 6)
    - Petition for Globes Workers, (undated) (Box 13)
    - Respect at LAX, (2003) (Box 5)
    - Sky Chefs, (2003) (Box 5)
    - Specialty Retail RFP, (2001) (Box 5)
    - Training for Ontario Airport (2 files), (undated) (Box 14)
    - Training Flyer for Ontario Airport, (2000) (Box 14)
  - Santa Monica Living Wage
    - 548 Building Workers' Compensation Claim Processing, (2006) (Box 20)
    - Anti-Retaliation Worker Retention Santa Monica, (2000) (Box 19)
    - Blue Cross, (2007) (Box 20)
    - Board Agendas, (1998-2000) (Box 20)
    - CA-1 (California One) correspondence - political activity, (2003) (Box 20)
    - Campaign Budget, (2002) (Box 11)
    - Campaign Finance Council, (2001) (Box 11)
    - CD paperwork, (2000) (Box 20)
    - Century Boulevard, (2006) (Box 20)
    - City of Santa Monica, (2001) (Box 19)
    - CLUE (Clergy and Laity United for Economic Justice), (1999) (Box 20)
    - CLUE (Clergy and Laity United for Economic Justice) Board, (1998-1999) (Box 20)
    - CLUE (Clergy and Laity United for Economic Justice) Board, (1999-2000) (Box 20)
    - CLUE (Clergy and Laity United for Economic Justice) Correspondence, (1997, 1999) (Box 20)
    - CLUE (Clergy and Laity United for Economic Justice) proposed activities, (1999-2000) (Box 20)
    - Coastal Zone Employers, (1999) (Box 16)
    - Double Tree, (2002) (Box 11)
    - Doubletree Hotel, (2002) (Box 19)
    - Doubletree Santa Monica, (2007) (Box 19)
    - Election (2 files), (2000) (Box 11)
    - Employment Policies Institute Foundation, (2000) (Box 12)
    - Environmental Report on 215 W. 6th, (2003) (Box 20)
    - EPI (Employment Policies Institute) Online, (1998, 2000) (Box 19)
    - FAIR (Fighting Against Irresponsible Regulations) (5 files), (2001) (Box 11)
    - Hearing (7/24), (1996) (Box 14)
      Appears to be related to Doubletree Hotel.
    - Hotel Initiative Santa Monica, (2000) (Box 19)
    - Hotels Santa Monica, (2000) (Box 19)
    - In Their Hands (VHS recording), (2003 Jun 4) (Box 35)
      Appears to be related to Santa Monica Living Wage campaign.
    - Jonathan Club Workers, (2000) (Box 19)
    - Journey towards Justice (Apr 17), (undated) (Box 14)
    - LAANE Organizational Manual, (undated) (Box 20)
    - LAANE's financial condition, (2001) (Box 20)
    - Legal Analysis General, (circa 1990) (Box 20)
    - Liberty Hill, (2002) (Box 11)
    - Living Wage Arguments, (1999) (Box 19)
    - Living Wage Ordinance and Supporting Materials, (2001) (Box 11)
    - Loews Action (June 26-29), (undated) (Box 14)
    - Loews Action (May 25), (undated) (Box 14)
    - Loews Hotel - Santa Monica, (2001) (Box 19)
    - Loews Santa Monica Beach Hotel, (2000, 2002) (Box 19)
    - Los Angeles Council Profiles, (2001) (Box 11)
    - Los Angeles Living Wage, (1996-1997) (Box 20)
    - Measure JJ (duplicates), (2000) (Box 19)
    - Measure JJ information packet, (undated) (Box 19)
    - Measure JJ Kick Off, (2002) (Box 19)
    - Miramar, (1997) (Box 19)
    - Miramar Report - Santa Monica Hotel, (1998) (Box 19)
    - Nader Action, (2000 May 30) (Box 16)
    - New Otani, (1997) (Box 20)
    - Nielsen Merksamer [Lobby Firm], (2002) (Box 12)
    - No on KK Materials, (2000) (Box 19)
    - Opposition Mailings on JJ, (2002) (Box 19)
    - Ordinance Displaced Workers, (1996) (Box 20)
    - Organization Structure, (undated) (Box 11)
    - Payments to Key Consultants, (2001-2002) (Box 11)
    - Phonebook Lists, (undated) (Box 20)
    - Plan for Corporate Accountability (A), (circa 1994) (Box 20)
    - Pollin Report, (2000) (Box 19)
    - Pritikin Center, (1997) (Box 19)
    - Prop KK (audio cassette recording), (undated) (Box 35)
    - Proposition KK information packet, (2000) (Box 19)
    - Public Hearings (scanned documents and visuals), (undated) (Box 19)
    - Religious Leaders and living wage, (2000, 2004) (Box 19)
    - Research Training, (1999) (Box 20)
    - Richard Berman EPI (Employment Policies Institute), (2000) (Box 19)
    - Rick Sander's Living Wage Study, (1997) (Box 19)
    - Santa Monica, (2001) (Box 19)
    - Santa Monica College, (1999) (Box 19)
    - Santa Monica Commission to investigate JJ election, (2003) (Box 19)
    - Santa Monica Email Lists, (circa 2000) (Box 16)
    - Santa Monica Hotel sponsored Living Wage Ordinance, (2000) (Box 11)
    - Santa Monica Hotel Sponsored Living Wage Ordinance Materials, (2000) (Box 19)
    - Santa Monica Hotels, (2002) (Box 19)
    - Santa Monica Living Wage, (2002) (Box 19)
    - Santa Monica Living Wage, (2000) (Box 19)
    - Santa Monica Living Wage, (2000) (Box 12)
    - Santa Monica Living Wage Coalition event script, (2000 May 30) (Box 14)
    - Santa Monica Living Wage Ordinance Proposal, (2001) (Box 7)
    - Santa Monica Living Wage Proposal Economic Analysis prepared by PERI (Political Economy Research Institute), (2000) (Box 25)
    - Santa Monica Living Wage Referendum Cross Tabulation Tables, (2002) (Box 25)
    - Santa Monica Policies: Legal Support, (1999) (Box 12)
    - Santa Monicans Allied for Responsible Tourism, (1999) (Box 7)
    - SMART (Santa Monicans Allied for Responsible Tourism), (2000) (Box 19)
    - SMART (Santa Monicans Allied for Responsible Tourism), (1997-2000) (Box 19)
    - SMART (Santa Monicans Allied for Responsible Tourism), (1997-1998) (Box 19)
    - SMART (Santa Monicans Allied for Responsible Tourism), (2002) (Box 19)
    - SMART (Santa Monicans Allied for Responsible Tourism) Campaign Finance, (2002) (Box 11)
    - SMART 'No on Measure KK' (SMH) footage (VHS recording), (undated) (Box 35)
    - Staff Training, (1999) (Box 20)
    - STEP (Strategic Training and Education for Power) program, (undated) (Box 20)
    - Tourism Layoffs (VHS tape), (2001 Oct) (Box 35)
    - Truth Team Legal, (2000) (Box 16)
    - Union Organizing Committee Loews Santa Monica Beach Hotel, (undated) (Box 13)
    - Wage Figure $10.69, (2001) (Box 16)
    - Worker Organizer Community Tourism Coordinator, (1999-2000) (Box 20)
    - Worker Relief Kick-off, (2001) (Box 11)
    - Worker Retention Ordinance Riordan Speaks Out, (1996) (Box 20)
    - Worker Stories, (undated) (Box 11)
    - Workers' Compensation, (2007) (Box 20)
    - Yes on JJ literature, (2002) (Box 19)
    - Yes on KK, (2000) (Box 19)
    - Yes on Proposition JJ, (2002) (Box 11)
  - Shop Well Los Angeles
    - AB 1060 Liquor KCAL (DVD-R recording), (2010 Sep 1) (Box 28)
    - Caravan: Supermarket Workers' Strike GRO (VHS recording), (2004 Jan 27-28) (Box 35)
    - Grocery Report (GGS) (DVD-R recording), (2007 Mar 21) (Box 28)
    - Grocery Workers Contract (GRO) (DVD-R recording), (2007 Mar 4) (Box 28)
    - Supermarkets Ramona Gardens (DVD-R recording), (2009 Oct 8) (Box 28)
    - Tale of Two Women: Cross L.A.'s Grocery Divide (A) (DVD recording), (undated) (Box 28)
  - Subsidy Policy 2000
    - CBA Hollywood and Highland, (1998) (Box 6)
    - LAX - Public Scoping Meetings, (1997) (Box 6)
    - Popular Education Packets Development, (2000) (Box 6)
    - Public Council Committee Development Project, (2000) (Box 6)
    - Public Subsidies Project, (2000) (Box 6)
    - Staples Expansion, (2000) (Box 6)
    - Subsidy Policy Development, (2000) (Box 6)
- Madeline Janis Files, 1994-2003
  The series consists of mostly of campaign-related files from the desk of Madeline Janis. The bulk of the files represent the Santa Monica Living Wage campaign. Included are copies of ordinances, measures, propositions, and studies. The files are arranged alphabetically by file title.
  - 7th and Grand Development Project, (2001) (Box 21)
    Related to Community Benefits Agreements.
  - Accountable Development, (2002-2003) (Box 21)
    Related to Santa Monica Living Wage.
  - Accountable Development, (2001-2002) (Box 21)
  - Adams - La Brea Project, (circa 2001) (Box 21)
  - Airport Correspondence General, (1995) (Box 22)
    Related to Los Angeles Living Wage.
  - American Society for Public Administration, (1998) (Box 12)
  - CLUE (Clergy and Laity United for Economic Justice), (1998-1999) (Box 22)
  - CRA (Community Redevelopment Agency) Policy, (2000) (Box 21)
    Related to Community Redevelopment Agency.
  - CRA (Community Redevelopment Agency) Presentations, (1999) (Box 22)
  - Draft Ordinances Airport, (1995) (Box 22)
  - Good Jobs List, (2001) (Box 22)
  - Holman Group, (1997) (Box 21)
  - Liberty Hill Collaborative Proposal, (1998) (Box 22)
  - Living Wage Election, (2002 Nov) (Box 21)
  - Living Wage Ordinance (and Amended Proposal), (1996) (Box 22)
  - Loews, (2000 Dec) (Box 21)
  - McDonalds Contract, (1994) (Box 22)
  - McDonalds worker list, (2002) (Box 22)
    Related to Respect at LAX.
  - NLRB (National Labor Relations Board) Elections, (undated) (Box 22)
  - PERI (Political Economy Research Institute) Study Santa Monica Living Wage, (1999-2000) (Box 21)
  - Personnel Committee Council File (LAX), (1995) (Box 22)
  - Personnel Committee Transcripts, (1995) (Box 22)
  - Pollin Study, (2000) (Box 21)
  - Possible Repeat Referendum, (2002 Nov) (Box 21)
  - Post 9/11, (2001) (Box 21)
  - Press Correspondence Santa Monica Living Wage, (2000) (Box 21)
  - Professor Alleyne's Letter, (1995 Jul 19) (Box 22)
  - Proposition KK, (undated) (Box 21)
  - Proposition KK, (undated) (Box 21)
  - Respect at LAX, (1998) (Box 22)
  - Respect at LAX Presentation, (1998-1999) (Box 22)
  - Sanders Study, (2000) (Box 21)
  - Santa Monica Campaign Disclosure Ordinance, (2001) (Box 21)
  - Santa Monica Campaign Finance, (2000) (Box 21)
  - Santa Monica Displaced Worker Ordinance, (2001) (Box 21)
  - Santa Monica Fundraising, (2000) (Box 21)
  - Santa Monica Referendum Campaign, (2001) (Box 21)
  - Staples Center, (2003) (Box 21)
    Related to Related to Community Benefits Agreements..
  - Sunquest, (2001 Nov 20) (Box 21)
  - Teamsters 911 Research, (2002) (Box 22)
  - Teamsters 911 Union Contract Information, (2002) (Box 22)
  - Walmart - Inglewood, (2003) (Box 22)
  - Walmart - Inglewood, (2003) (Box 22)
  - Walmart Campaign - Super Markets, (2003) (Box 22)
  - Worker Defense, (1997) (Box 15)
  - Worker Retention Articles and Updates, (1995) (Box 22)
  - Worker Retention General Opposition, (1995-1996) (Box 22)
  - Worker Retention Legal Analysis, (1995 Apr 28) (Box 22)
  - Worker Retention Materials, (1996) (Box 22)
  - Worker Retention Ordinance Proposed Amendments, (1996) (Box 22)
- Vivian Rothstein Files, 1997-2010
  The series consists of mostly of campaign-related files from the desk of Vivian Rothstein. The bulk of the files represent Respect at LAX, and Santa Monica Living Wage campaigns, among others. The files include a mixture of documents and are arranged alphabetically by file title.
  - City Council proposal, (2004 Jan 13) (Box 23)
  - City Wide Hotel Contract Campaign, (2004) (Box 24)
  - Commission letters and articles, (2003) (Box 23)
  - Commission report, (2003) (Box 23)
  - Council Rally, (2000 Mar 27) (Box 24)
  - Displaced Worker Protection, (2001) (Box 23)
  - Diversity Hiring Outreach, (2009-2010) (Box 24)
    Related to Coalition for a New Century.
  - Diversity Issue, (2004-2006) (Box 24)
  - Diversity Task Force, (2007-2008) (Box 25)
  - Election Finances, (2002) (Box 23)
  - Four Points, (2000-2002) (Box 23)
  - Four Points Hotel, (2003) (Box 23)
  - HITEP (Hospitality Industry Training and Education Plan) Contract, (2009-2010) (Box 25)
  - Hotel Boycott, (2004) (Box 24)
  - Kick off, (2002 Sep 22) (Box 23)